（雷鳴）
Black Vinegar Private Middle School
Man, what a surprise.
（エクボ）
いやあ しかし たまげたぜ
I guess there are espers
other than you, Shigeo.
茂夫(しげお)以外にも いたんだな？
超能力者
（エクボ）
だけど ビックラこいてんのは
あちらさんも同じようだぜ？
But it looks like he's
pretty surprised himself.
Impossible...
（テル）
バカな… お前 ナチュラルか？
Are you a natural?
僕のほかにも いたなんて！
There's another like me?
What is the creepy-looking
ball of energy next to you?
（テル）
隣の気色悪い造形のエネルギー体は
何だ？
はあ？
What?
Are you its master?
（テル）
お前が使役してるのか？
No, it's haunting me.
（モブ）
いや 取りつかれてる
Well, whatever.
（テル）
まあ いい！
聞きたいことは いくつかあるけど
There are a bunch of questions
I want to ask you,
but before that, we need
to establish something...
その前に
ハッキリさせとかないとね
The hierarchy here.
上下関係ってやつをさ！
Say what?
何 それ？
Progress Towards
Mob's Explosion
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 45%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 46%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 47%
～
Mob Psycho
OCHIMUSHA
~Psychic Powers and Me~
Be careful just in case, Shigeo.
（エクボ）
一応 気をつけろ！ 茂夫
Even you could get tripped up
if you're not care—
いくら お前でも
油断してると 足をすくわれるぞ
Sorry, I wasn't listening.
ごめん 聞いてなかった
なに？
What?!
どうして攻撃してくるの？
Why are you attacking me?
I haven't done anything.
僕は何もしてないよ？ 仲良く…
Let's be...
クククッ 警戒してんな～
He's on guard.
Not that I don't understand how he feels.
（エクボ）
ヤツの気持ちも
分からんではないがな
I bet he's lived his life so far as
the big fish in a very small pond.
（エクボ）
恐らく今まで ず～っと
小さな池の主として生きてきたんだ
And for the first time ever, he's meeting
someone that could be his natural enemy.
自分の天敵になりえる存在に
遭うのは 人生初
If he doesn't establish
his superiority right now,
この場で自分の優位性を
証明しないと
he won't be satisfied, I'm sure.
収まりが
つかないんだろうな
But, that aside...
それは さておき…
What's with those weird movements?
They're kinda like wire action.
（エクボ）
あのワイヤーアクションみたいな
変な動きは何だ？
Telekinesis.
（モブ）
念動力だよ
物を浮かせたりするやつ
It lets you move objects around, and stuff.
お前は やらないのか？
You're not gonna do it?
（モブ）酔うから やらない
（エクボ）へ？
I get nauseous, so no.
I use telekinesis to teleport
close to my opponent
（テル）
念動推進力による高速移動で近づき
and blow him away with my Psycho Fist.
サイコ掌打で吹っ飛ばす！
This dancing strategy that I've perfected
to use against average people
対 凡人用として完成された
この“ダンシング戦法”が
apparently looks like nothing more
than weird movements against him.
あいつの前では
ただの変な動きに成り下がった！
くっ チクショ～！
Damn it!
Shigeo, you need to teach him a lesson here.
茂夫 ここは ひとつ
分からせてやれよ！
上には上がいるってことをよ
Show him who's boss.
Come on. Look at how he's standing.
He's gonna attack again.
（エクボ）
ほら あいつ また何か
内股で仕掛けてくるぞ？
You need to hit him with something big, too.
お前も早く
ド～ンとやり返してやれ！
No.
嫌だよ　超能力は
人に向けていいものじゃないんだ
You're not supposed to use
psychic powers against people.
You idiot! Look at who you're talking about!
バッカ！ お前 相手を見てみろ
He's put his psychic powers to good use
and is living a fulfilling life!
（エクボ）
超能力をうまく利用して
充実ライフを送ってんじゃねえか！
And then look at you.
それに対して お前はどうだ？
You live a dull lifestyle,
with one boring day after another.
地味な性格 さえない日常…
超能力のないお前に
魅力なんか あると思うか？
Do you think there's anything appealing
about you without your psychic powers?
Listen up!
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
いいか？ よく聞け！
俺たちは
人とは違う特別な“力”を
We were born with special powers
that other people don't have,
生まれ持ったわけだが
but we mustn't let it get to our heads
and think we're special.
決して 自分を特別な存在だと
勘違いしてはいけない
People who are fast,
足が速い人
39th Choral Competition
people who sing well,
歌がうまい人
people who are book smart,
勉強ができる人
people who are good at talking,
話が面白い人
and people who can use psychic powers...
超能力を使える人
You can't put one over the other.
これらに優劣など付けられるか？
Being confident about your powers is fine,
but you mustn't get conceited.
“力”に自信を持つのはいいが
おごっては いかんぞ！
Depending on how we use our powers,
they can also be deadly weapons.
俺たちの“力”は
使い方しだいで凶器にもなる
They're just like knives.
刃物と同じだ
What are you not supposed to do with knives?
刃物で やっちゃいけないこと
といえば 何だ？
Point them at people?
（モブ）
人に向ける？
So you do get it.
Make sure you never forget that.
よく分かってんじゃねえか
肝に銘じておけ！
That's the moral code people like us
with special powers need to live by.
（霊幻）
それが 特別な“力”を持つ
俺たちのモラルだ
That all gets ruined once
you know Reigen said it.
霊幻が言うと台なしだな！
Anyway, I won't use them in a fight.
とにかく ケンカには使わない！
それに—
Also, I don't want to live a life
having to rely on psychic powers.
僕は超能力に頼った生き方は
したくない！
I'm going to find some other
potential within me.
（モブ）
自分の中のほかの魅力を探すんだ
Not to mention, I started working out.
筋トレだって始めたし…
僕は変わるんだ！
I'm going to change.
You say that, but...
（エクボ）
変わるったって お前…
（エクボ）茂夫！
Shigeo!
How about that?!
（テル）
今度はどうだ？
That was a telekinetic tackle
with all my weight behind it.
全体重を乗せた念動タックルだ！
“超能力を使わない生き方”だと？
A life without using psychic powers?
ふん！ バカだな！
How stupid!
There's no reason to live your life
stooping to the level of average people!
（テル）
わざわざ 凡人どもに合わせて
生きる必要なんてないのに！
その他の魅力など
クソの役にも立たないよ！
Other potentials are absolutely useless!
Working out? Studying?
（テル）
筋トレ？ 勉強？
Leave all that crap to the average people!
そんなのは凡人にやらせとけ～！
Brain, brawn, and even the law
are all powerless before my gift!
（テル）
僕の“力”の前では
腕力も学力も 法律すら無力だ！
I'm special, and the world
revolves around me!
僕は特別な存在
この世界の中心なんだよ！
Jeez, I guess there's no choice.
（エクボ）
ったく しょうがねえな～
あっ？
Hey, little boy. How about
we just call this a draw?
なあ 坊や 今回は
引き分けで納得してくれねえか？
Not happening.
断る！
あんなヤツと引き分けなんて
僕の人生の汚点になる
Ending up in a draw with a guy like that
would be the biggest disgrace in my life.
I can't have you breaking Shigeo, either.
こっちとしても—
茂夫をここで
壊されるわけには いかねんだわ
He has no intention of fighting back,
so he's obviously going to lose.
（エクボ）
反撃の意思がないから
このままじゃ負ける！
That... wouldn't be good.
それは…
困る！
Dimple?
（モブ）
エクボ？
Most of my spiritual power's been erased,
（エクボ）
茂夫に霊力のほとんどを消されて
so I'm pretty much just some
scraps left over, but...
今は残りカスみたいなもんだが
Even then, I shouldn't have any problems
disciplining a cocky little brat.
それでも うぬぼれたガキ１匹
教育するぐらい
わけねえと思うぜ？
茂夫は神になれる男だ
Shigeo's a man who can become a god.
He's not a second-rate loser like—
てめえみたいな
二流を相手にしねえ…
えっ？
Huh?
Dimple!
エクボ？
I erased that thing with my Psycho Wave.
（テル）
僕のサイコウェーブで消し飛ばした
From the core, so there wouldn't
be a single shred left.
ひとかけらも残さず 根元からね
Dimple's been exorcised...
エクボが 除霊された？
Progress Towards
Mob's Explosion
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 47%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 48%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 49%
Progress Toward Mob's Explosion: 50%
Forget about your club.
（エクボ）
部活 辞めちまえよ～
Work on your psychic powers instead!
それより 超能力を磨け！
Tsubomi-chan, eh? She's got a nice ass.
へえ ツボミちゃんか～
いいケツしてんじゃん
Who the hell are you calling a ladybug?!
誰がテントウムシだ？ こら！
I'm gonna send your master to the hospital.
お前の師匠
入院させてやろうか～？
I'll make you popular.
俺様が
お前を人気者にしてやるよ！
Hey! Want me to show you
how to use X-ray vision?
なっ 透視のやり方
教えてほしいか？
I don't know either, you perv!
俺様も知らねえよ！
ドスケベめ～
Just for a sec, would you
let me take over your body?
一瞬でいいからさ
試しに体を乗っ取らせて
くれねえか？
エクボ…
Dimple...
What? Are you so shocked
that your pet was erased?
どうした？
ペットを消されたのが
そんなにショックか？
Not really.
そうでもない
Progression Toward Mob's Explosion: 50%
（テル）
うっ…
チッ！ まっ そうだろうな
Yeah, I guess you wouldn't be...
After all, it was sort of a pointless
existence to begin with.
元から
何の意味もない存在だからな
それは お前も同じだがな
Though that goes for you, too.
僕の前では所詮 三流…
小物でしかない！
Compared to me, you're third-rate.
Nothing but small fry.
You can become big! I guarantee it!
（エクボ）
お前は大物になるぜ！
俺様が保証する～！
こう言っておかないと
勘違いするバカがいるんだ！
Some idiots get the wrong idea
if things aren't spelled out for them.
They think they can be someone
if they actually try.
（テル）
“こんな自分でも
努力すれば何かになれる”ってね！
Be more confident, Shigeo!
After all, you're the main character!
（エクボ）
もっと自信を持て 茂夫！
主役はお前だぜ～
うっ…
What? What's with that look?
何だよ お前 その顔は？
あのさ…
なんで“小物”とか“凡人”とか
Hey, why do you have to belittle others
by calling them average or small fry?
いちいち
他人を下げないといけないのかな？
はあ？
Wha?
いや… 彼は意外と
いいヤツだったのかもしれないと
Well, I just realized that he might
actually have been an okay guy, that's all...
気付いただけ
Compared to you.
（モブ）
あんたと比べてみて
What?
何だと？
（雷鳴）
（テル）
お前…
Don't...
think that you can keep that
smug look on your face forever!
（テル）
いつまでも余裕面で
いられると思うな～！
僕の超能力で屈服させてやる！
I'll make you submit to me
with my psychic powers!
I'm gonna come at you with
full power and no brakes!
出力最大！ ノーブレーキでいくよ
（モブ）
危ないよ
僕じゃなかったらケガしちゃう
That's dangerous.
If it wasn't me, you could hurt someone.
やめなよ
Stop that.
Are you trying to say that
you won't get hurt?
（テル）
お前だったら
ケガしないって言うのか？
Quit underestimating my powers!
僕の“力”を
甘く見てんじゃねえ～！
うう～ うっ！
あああ～！
うお！
What's wrong? You just going
to keep defending yourself?
（テル）
どうした？
守ってばかりか？
やめろって言ってんのに…
I told you to stop that.
お前の“力”を見せてみろ！
Show me your powers!
（テル）
見せないつもりなら
少し趣向を変えようか？
If you're not going to show me your powers,
I guess we'll have to try something else.
I'll just see how much you can take
by administering an endurance test.
どこまで耐えられるか
耐久テストをしてやるよ！
ううう～！
ああああ～！
くいいい～！
（モブ）
あっ…
イテッ！
Ow.
The home ec room.
家庭科室か…
包丁は危ないよ　人に向けちゃ…
Knives are dangerous. You shouldn't point—
Don't order me around.
You'll reduce your lifespan that way.
僕に指図するな！
早死にするぞ？ お前
Of course, I have no
intention of killing him,
（テル）
もちろん 殺す気なんてないが
これで反撃する気になるだろう
but I'm sure he'll feel like
fighting back now.
いいかげんに
事故が起きるってば！
Will you stop? This is going
to cause an accident.
えっ？
Huh?
うっ…
You did this on purpose, didn't you?
（テル）
お前 わざとやっただろ？ これ…
えっ？
A huge accident has occurred.
（モブ）
大事故が起きた！
（テル）
くくっ… ぶっ！
I'm going to kill you!
ぶっ殺す！
Top of
Teru's Head
Top of Teru's Head 0%
Mob Psycho
（雷鳴）
You'll pay for this.
（テル）
お前は もう許さねえ！
謝っても 許さねえからな！
I won't forgive you, even if you apologize!
ふん！
あっ…
はっ お前…
You...
（テル）
今 “より一層 落ち武者っぽく
なった”とか思っただろ？
You totally thought I look even more
like an ochimusha now, didn't you?
えっ？ 言ってない！
Huh? I didn't say that.
So you did think it.
（テル）
思ったんだな？
いや… いい！ 分かっている
No, that's fine. I'll admit it.
This shameful sight! This truth!
認めよう この醜態！ この事実！
And I'll acknowledge you, too.
そして 認めるよ　お前のことも
What's your name?
名前は何ていうんだい？
影山(かげやま)… 影山茂夫
Kageyama... Kageyama Shigeo.
Kageyama... I'm Hanazawa. Hanazawa Teruki.
（テル）
影山… 僕は花沢だ　花沢輝気(はなざわてるき)
花沢君 どうも！ よろしく
Hi, Hanazawa-kun. Nice to meet you.
No, not as a friend.
（テル）
違うよ！ 友ではない
敵として認めるんだ！
I acknowledged you as an enemy.
そうすることで
より本気になれる！
By doing that, I can get even
more serious about this.
ふぉ～！
S-Stop this already.
（モブ）
もっ もうやめようよ！ うっ…
If you want to stop this, make me stop!
（テル）
終わらせたければ
打ち負かしてみろ！
おら おら おら！ どうした？
Come on, come on, come on! What's wrong?
反撃しないと大ケガするぞ！
Fight back, or you'll wind up badly hurt!
相手は僕なんだ！
You're dealing with me!
I'm popular, and the
main character of the world!
僕は人気者で 世界の主役！
全ては僕を中心に回ってるんだ！
Everything revolves around me!
花沢輝気は選ばれた存在なんだ！
Hanazawa Teruki is the chosen one!
なんで？ なんで そこまで
自分に自信が持てるの？
Why? How can you be so
confident in yourself?
What a stupid question!
（テル）
愚問だね
It's because I have psychic powers!
僕には超能力があるからだ！
全てを支配する力だ！
It's the power to control all!
And you are my first enemy!
そして お前は
僕にとっての初めての敵！
Now, attack me!
Let's have a test of strength!
さあ 攻撃してこい！
力比べだ！
嫌だよ
No.
どうしてだ？
Why?! I'm telling you that it's okay!
僕がいいと言ってるんだぞ？
だって 大ケガをさせたくない
Because... I don't want to
injure you really badly.
Wha?
はあ？
ハッハッハッハッ 面白い冗談だ！
What a funny joke!
僕を凡人どもと 一緒にするなよ
Don't compare me to those average people.
僕とヤツらでは
生物としてのレベルが違う！
I'm on a completely different level
than them as living creatures.
超能力が使えるくらいで
そこまで？
Being able to use psychic
powers isn't that...
What?
（テル）
何だと？
Oh, well, I just thought you were
going a bit overboard.
あっ いや 少し大げさかなって…
（テル）
お前だけだよ
そんな反論ができるのは！
You're the only person who
could make that argument.
だから 邪魔なんだ！
お前みたいなのは
That's why you're an eyesore!
あれ？ 分かった
Oh, I just realized why you
hold such animosity toward me.
なんで そんなに
僕に敵意を向けるのか
You don't like me because we're the same.
（モブ）
これは“同族嫌悪”だ
You're sort of like me, Hanazawa-kun...
花沢君は僕に少し似てる
Not the fact that we both
have psychic powers,
超能力を持ってるところじゃなくて
自分に全然 自信がないところ
but the fact that you have no confidence
in yourself, just like me.
自分から超能力を取ったら
何も残らない
If you take away your psychic powers,
there'll be nothing left.
You'll be empty.
空っぽなんだ！
それに気付くのが怖いんだ
You're scared of that realization.
No friends, and no standing out.
友達も少ない
目立たなくて 何の記録も残せない
脇役の凡人
Just another average loser
who won't leave a mark.
それが僕
That's me.
Deep down, you're the same as me.
（モブ）
花沢君の正体も僕と同じなんだ
超能力がないと何もできない
ってことを認めたくないんだと思う
You just don't want to admit that you're
nothing without your psychic powers—
No!
違う！ 寝言を言うな！
Quit dreaming! The two of us
are completely different!
僕とお前じゃ
何もかも違うだろ～！
同じだよ
僕から見れば 凡人だもの
We're the same.
From my perspective, you're totally average.
黙れ～！
Shut up!
（モブ）
ううっ…
He's not using his powers...
（モブ）
超能力が こもってない？
（テル）
ううう…
僕は何をしている？
What am I doing? How did this happen?
なぜこうなった？
クソッ お前だ　お前のせいだ！
Damn it, it's you! This is all your fault!
常にパーフェクトだった
Everything was perfect.
（男子生徒）
輝(てる)君 また100点 取ったの？
Teru-kun, you got another perfect score?
As long as I used my powers,
（テル）
“力”さえ使えば
何もかも思いどおりになった
everything went exactly
how I wanted it to go.
What was that shot? That was amazing!
（男子生徒）
何だよ 今のシュート！
スッゲえ～！
We're sorry! Please forgive us!
（男子生徒たち）
すいませんでした！
もう勘弁してください！
（テル）
そんな僕の世界を…
And yet, you took my world...
U-Um... I made some cookies,
if you'd like some.
（女子生徒）
クッキー作ったんで よかったら
（テル）
お前が… お前という存在が
You... Your existence...
destroyed that!
（テル）
ぶち壊した！
チクショ～！
Damn it!
使え！ 超能力を使え～！
Use them! Use your psychic powers!
うっ… がはっ…
ダメ… だ…
No...
（モブ）
人に… 向け… たら
I can't use them...
ダメだ！
against people!
（テル）
来るか？
Is he coming?!
うっ…
何だよ それ？
What the heck was that?
Just how much are you going to
keep rejecting me?
（テル）
どこまで僕を否定する気だ？
Hey, Kageyama. Didn't you say
that you started working out?
なあ 影山
筋トレを始めたと言っていたな？
That means that no matter how hard
you try, that's all you've got.
努力しても
所詮 その程度ということだ！
（モブ）
あっ あ…
人は そう簡単に変われないんだよ
People can't change that easily.
Just give it up. Use your psychic powers.
もう諦めろ　超能力を使え！
Otherwise, I'm going to...
でないと 僕はお前を…
Give it back!
（影山 律(りつ)）
返してよ！
Give us back our New Year's money!
僕たちのお年玉 返してよ！
Don't get so cocky, brat. I'll kill you.
（高校生）
小学生が調子こくなよ　殺すぞ！
（モブ）律！
（高校生）てめえは どいてろ！
Ritsu!
You stay out of this!
（高校生たち）ハッハッハッ
（律）兄さん！
Nii-san!
（モブ）
はっ！
Nii-sa...
（律）
兄さん…
It hurts, Nii-san...
痛いよ… 兄さん
I'm going to change.
（モブ）
変わる！
I won't use them.
使わない！
I'm going to change.
僕は変わるんだ！
Huh? Hey, Kageyama?
（テル）
えっ？ おい 影山？
Hey... Hey! Wake up!
おい… おい 起きろよ！
Wait! Don't leave me behind!
待て 僕を置いてくな！
Kageyama...
影山… あ…
Kageyama Shigeo and Hanazawa Teruki.
（ナレーション）
影山茂夫と花沢輝気
The battle between these two espers
never reached its conclusion.
超能力者同士の対決は
ついに決着がつかなかった
互いのよりどころを
拒絶し合った結果
As a result of rejecting each other's ideals,
there was no victor,
そこに勝者はなく
and they were only left with a feeling
of emptiness deep in their hearts.
虚無感のみが両者の胸に
深く刻まれる結果となった
Or so it seemed...
…かに思えた
（テル）
あっ…
くっ… 何だ？ それは
What... is that?
Do you finally feel like fighting?
（テル）
やっと やる気になったのか？
Good! In the end, you couldn't
stay true to your ideals, either!
それでいい！
結局 お前も信念を貫けないんだ！
Bring it! Ultimate Barrier!
よし 来た！ 最大バリア！
うっ… ぐはっ！
クックックッ…
You used them! Kageyama!
使ったな？ 影山！
You finally couldn't stand it anymore
and used your psychic powers!
我慢できずに
超能力を使いやがった！
てめえも
人に向けて使ってんじゃねえか！
You used them against another person!
結局 お前も…
（テル）
あれ？ こいつ 意識がないのか？
Huh?
Is he unconscious?
Then what the hell is this power?
じゃあ 何だよ？ この“力”
What...
何だ？ ん？
僕の“力”が
影山に吸い込まれていく
My powers are being sucked in by Kageyama...
No, that's not all... All of the
energy in the atmosphere...
いや それだけじゃない！
大気中のエネルギーも？
Are you telling me his vessel
is able to handle this much?
こんな膨大な器を持っていたのか？
Teru sensed in there something
that must never be touched.
（ナレーション）
テルは そこに触れてはいけない
何かを感じていた
異質　正体不明
Something incomparable, its identity unknown.
ひぃ！
You're kidding... What in
the world did I awaken?
（テル）
ウソだろ？
僕は
何を目覚めさせてしまったんだ？
わっ わっ あああああ～！
もう十分だ！ 僕が悪かったよ～！
That's enough! I'm sorry!
超能力は
もう人に向けないから～！
I won't use my psychic powers
against other people!
ああ 僕って
Oh, I guess...
I'm actually just an average person...
凡人… だったんだな
It didn't take long for Mob to realize.
（ナレーション）
モブは すぐに悟った
“自分は
変わることができなかった”
He failed to change.
He caused another accident
because of his psychic powers.
“また 超能力で
事故を起こしてしまった”
He didn't know where to direct his emotions.
感情をぶつける先が見つからない
He was overwhelmed, his powerlessness
born from contradictions.
矛盾をはらむ無力感にのまれる
The feeling that he would never
be able to conquer himself...
どうしても
自分に勝てないという—
Sadness.
悲しみ
This was Mob's meager attempt
at resistance towards himself.
それは モブの 自らに対する
ささやかな抵抗であった
Hanazawa-kun, um...
（モブ）
花沢君 あの… 服とか ごめん
I'm sorry about your clothes an—
W-Wait! Kageyama, I'm...
（テル）
まっ 待て！ 影山
僕は もう…
（枝野 剛(えだの　つよし)）
うっ イテテ…
ケンカは どうなったんだ？
Ow... What happened with the fight?
（ヤンキー）
ああ テルさんだ
いたぞ！ あそこだ
It's Teru-san! He's right over there.
は？ 何だ あれ？
Huh? What the hell?
（枝野）
うわ～！
えげつなく処刑されてるぞ！
He's been brutally executed!
あっ あんな頭にされて
たまるか～
I-I'm not gonna let that happen to my hair!
Those guys...
あいつら…
フッ 見たろ？ 影山
You just saw it, Kageyama.
It's just as you said...
（モブ）
あっ…
君の言ったとおりだ
僕たちから超能力を取ったら何も…
If you take away our psychic powers...
Kageyama-kun!
（男子生徒）
影山君！
Ah, guys...
（モブ）
あっ みんな！
Hey, Kageyama, are you hurt?
（郷田武蔵(ごうだむさし)）
おい 影山 ケガはないのか？
I'm fine.
（モブ）
僕は大丈夫ですけど…
All right, then, good.
（郷田）
よし！ なら いい！
We're gonna go back and do more squats!
今日は もう帰って スクワットだ！
There's nothing I can even say.
（テル）
言い訳できないな
I completely lost.
完敗だよ
Under
Construction
Mob searched for about three hours,
but he couldn't find Dimple.
（ナレーション）
３時間ほど捜したが
結局 エクボは見つからなかった
I'm home.
（モブ）
ただいま
ハア…
（律）
兄さん？
Nii-san?
（律）
おかえり 風邪ひくよ
Welcome home. You're gonna catch a cold.
Thanks.
（モブ）
ありがとう
今日は遅かったね　ご飯は？
You're home late today. Do you want to eat?
Nah. I'm gonna head to bed.
（モブ）
いいや　もう寝るよ
何か元気ないね　どうかした？
You seem down. Did something happen?
何かあったら 相談に乗るからね！
If you need to talk, I'll be
happy to listen. Good night.
おやすみ
Ritsu.
（モブ）律！
（律）ん？
I'm sorry about that one time.
モブ）
あのときは ごめんね
あのとき？
That one time?
兄さんが車に酔って 僕の
パーカーのフードに吐いたとき？
You mean when you got carsick and
threw up into the hood of my jacket?
No... Well, I'm sorry about that, too.
（モブ）
いや… まあ そのときも ごめん
超能力の事故のとき…
I really can't remember what happened
with that accident
involving my psychic powers.
どうしても思い出せないんだ
あのとき 僕は
律に何をしたんだろう？
What... did I do to you back then?
Oh, you mean when those high school kids
picked a fight with us.
（律）
ああ 高校生に絡まれたときのね
兄さんには何もされてないよ
You didn't do anything to me, Nii-san.
One of the punks kicked
me away, and I got hurt.
不良が僕を突き飛ばして
ケガをしただけさ
But you protected me, Nii-san.
兄さんは 僕を守ってくれたんだよ
いつまでも
気にすることじゃない！
You should get over it already. Good night.
おやすみ
ああ…
Today, after 5 PM, countless
people have reported seeing
（キャスター）
今日 午後５時過ぎ
雷雨 激しい調味(ちょうみ)市の空にて
a supernatural phenomenon in the stormy
skies above Seasoning City.
怪奇現象が起きたとの目撃情報が
相次いでおります
(An ochimusha) was flying!
Among the rubble,
上昇するがれきの中には
人のようなものも見え
there were also reports of what looked
like a person flying up into the air,
いまだ
被害者の特定および安否が…
but we have not been able to confirm
any victims or their well-being.
（律）
あのとき…
Back then...
（モブ）
律！
Ritsu!
You stay out of this!
（高校生）
てめえは どいてろ！
あっ…
Nii-san!
（律）
兄さ～ん！
（キャスター）
一部では
人為的に起こされた超常現象…
A Supernatural Phenomenon in the
Skies Above Seasoning City!?
Footage Submitted by a Viewer
The theory that this was man-made
is gaining traction.
That wasn't Nii-san.
（律）
あれは 兄さんじゃなかった
I have no appetite.
（モブ）
食欲がない
He caught a cold.
（ナレーション）
風邪をひいた
～
His overwhelming desire for psychic powers
makes Ritsu-kun stray from the right path.
（霊幻）
超能力に憧れるあまり
道を踏み外す律君
そんなこととは つゆ知らず
Having no idea that was happening,
Mob goes on a carefree date with Tome.
モブは のんきに
トメとデートに明け暮れる？
おいおい モブ！
Hey, now, Mob. This isn't the time for that!
んなこと
やってる場合じゃねえぞ？
次回「モブサイコ100」
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Episode 6:
第６話“不調和　成るために”
"Discord ~To Become One~"
初回仕様？ 最も正しい判断です！
Discord
~To Become One~
First-press limited edition?
That is the absolute best decision.